A Guide to the Wadsworth and Carter Receipts, 1782-1783
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Wadsworth and Carter Reciepts, 1782-1783.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 84.2
14 items.
Wadsworth and Carter (Firm); John Barker Church, 1746-1818.; Jeremiah Wadsworth, 1743-1804.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1984.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm M-1561.
Biographical/Historical Information
The firm of Wadsworth and Carter was the creation of Jeremiah Wadsworth and Colonel Carter. Carter was actually John Barker Church. They served as agents for the French Army during the Revolutionary War.
Scope and Content Information
Bills and receipts of the firm Wadsworth and Carter. Documents relate to circumstances surrounding the Battle of Yorktown, October 1781, primarily concerning the return of wagons and teams of horses. Other receipts cover shoeing horses, traveling, recruiting army drivers, supplying food grains, straw, wood, and salt, and labor costs. Mentioned specifically are Count de Rochambeau, Marquis de Lafayette, and the "Duke's [Lauzun] Legion" in Hampton, [Va.]. There is also mention of Samuel Beale, J. Cammill, John Davis, John Debow, Mark Garrett, B. H. Holmes, Christian Ish, Thomas Lewis, Warner Lewis, Daniel Moore, Levi Pease, J. Penon, Benjamin Powell, and Daniel Rogan.
Arrangement
Chronologically arranged.
Index Terms
Persons:
Biron, Armand-Louis de Gontaut, duc de, 1747- 1793.; Cammill, J.; Church, John Barker, 1746-1818.; Davis, John, fl. 1775-1783.; Debow, John.; Garrett, Mark.; Holmes, B. H., fl. 1776-1783.; Ish, Christian.; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert Du Motier, marquis de, 1757-1834.; Lewis, Thomas, 1718- 1790.; Lewis, Warner, b. 1720.; Moore, Daniel.; Penor, J.; Powell, Benjamin, d. 1791.; Rochambeau, Jean-Baptiste-Donatien de Vimeur, comte de, 1725-1807.; Rogan, Daniel.; Wadsworth, Jeremiah, 1743-1804.
Corporate Names:
France--Armee--Commissariat.; Lauzon's Legion.; Wadsworth and Carter (Firm)
Geographical Names:
Gloucester (Va.); Hampton (Va.); United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783--Campaigns.; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783-- Confiscations and contributions.; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783--Participation, French.; Williamsburg (Va.)--History--Revolution, 1775-1783.
Contents List
- Receipt, 1 Jan. 1782.
  Receipt for the return of waggon's etc. under the command of Maj. John Davis, Williamsburgh to Messrs. Wadsworth and Carter. Includes the names of the four conductors: J. W. Shields, Jos. Broadhurst, Thomas Gardner and Thomas Scott.
- Receipt, 8 Jan. 1782.
  Receipt for the return of wagons and other items under the command of Maj. John Davis in Williamsburg to Messrs. Wadsworth and Carter. Conductors are listed as Ben. Smith Jos. Broadhurst and Thomas Scott.
- Receipt, 10 Jan. 1782.
  Receipt for the return of wagons etc. under the command of Maj. John Davis, Williamsburg, to Messrs. Wadsworth and Carter. Lists the conductors as: John Davis, Broadhurst and Seaman, Benj. Smith and Thomas Scott.
- Receipt, 11 Jan 1782
  Receipt for the return of wagons, etc. under the command of Maj. John Davis, Williamsburg, to Messrs. Wadsworth and Carter. Lists conductors as: John Davis, Ben. Smith, Broadhurst and Seaman and Thomas Scott.
- Receipt, 12 Feb 1782.
  Receipt for six bushels of corn and eight bushels of barley received for the French Army. Signed by a French soldier.
- Receipt, 28 Feb 1782.
  Receipt for six bushels of corn and eight bushels of barley received by Thomas Lewis for Warner Lewis from Messrs. Wadsworth and Carter.
- Receipt, 29 Mar 1782
  Receipt, signed by Danl. Rogan acknowledging his receipt of nine crowns from Wadsworth and Carter. Rogan received payment for raising drivers for the army.
- Receipt, 21 Apr. 1782
  Statement for return of wagons and horses from a brigade of the French Army at Rockspring Camp. Signed by J. Cammill.
- Receipt, 23 Apr. 1782
  Receipt for the return of horses and teams from an unnamed Army brigade. Signed by Danl. Mooreville for his brigade.
- Receipt, 26 Apr 1782.
  Receipt signed by Christian Ish, Lancaster, acknowledging payment from Levi Pease for shoeing horses.
- Receipt, 18 May 1782.
  Receipt signed by B. Holmes, York, acknowledging payment from Messrs. Wadsworth and Carter for the use of "Shipp of Rochambeau."
- Statement, 12 Sep-13 Sep 1782.
  Statement from John Debow, Pompton Plains, for goods and services supplied to Wadsworth and Carter as agents for the French Army.
- Receipt, 19 Dec. 1782-8 Feb. [1783]
  Receipt signed by Mark Garrett, on behalf of the American Army, acknowledging payment from Messrs. Wadsworth and Carter for supplies delivered to the French Army. The supplies were delivered to the French troops at Jamestown by order of Lafayette; also, for the delivery of salt to Mr. Reynaud.
- Receipt, 1 July 1783.
  Receipt signed by Benjamin Powell acknowledging receipt of payment from Danl. Alcott for his services as a driver in the employ of Wadsworth and Carter.